# **RAVINDRA NATH BURA**

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## **Profile Summary**

Full-Stack Developer with 4+ years of experience in Optimizing Applications for maximum speed and scalability. Efficient in Co-operating with other front-end developers and product managers to solve any challenging problems. Competent in Designing and Developing web applications across multiple APIs, third party integrations and databases.

#### **Contact Details**

- □ ravindr283@gmail.com
- \$\square\$ +91 87704-08771
- Pelikhalli, Bengaluru, India
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/ravi ndranathbura/

#### **Technical Skills**

- Tech-Language
  - Node js, React js, TypeScript, JavaScript, Angular, Next js, Nest js, Laravel, PHP
- Database
  - MySql, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Version-Control
  - Git, Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket
- Cloud
  - AWS S3-Bucket, AWS API-gateway, AWS-Cognito, Lamda
- Other
  - ML, GraphQL, Prisma, TypeOrm, Docker, Kubernetes

## **Educational Background**

• Bachelor of Engineering

Shri Yogendra Sagar Institute of Technology

#### **Certifications**

- Machine Learning, Tata group (E-learning)
- Junior Software Developer, (P.M.K.V.Y)

#### **Soft Skills**

- Teamwork
- Problem Solving
- Time Management

# Professional Experience

**Sr. Software Developer** (2020 – Present) Arokee Online Solution Pvt. Ltd. | Bengaluru Key responsibilities:

- Overseeing back-end/front-end development using PHP, Node-js, React js, and Angular 12, to maintain website integrity, security, and efficiency.
- Used PHP, JS, Node-js, React js, Angular-12, MySQL, MongoDB Payment Module Integration, Google Maps APIs, Agora video call, and KYC integration.
- Building databases and table structures following architecture methodology for web applications.
- Entered system was based on MVC architecture implemented using the Laravel MVC framework.
- Developed Rest Services with microservices.

## Junior Software Developer (2019 – 2020)

Teleperformance | Bengaluru Key responsibilities:

- Wrote SQL scripts to create DB tables.
- Involved in DB design.
- Involved in the design, analysis, development, testing, deployment, and support phase of the application.

#### **Achievements**

2022 – 2023	<b>Best Performer of The Year</b> , Arokee Online Solutions Pvt. Ltd
2021 – 2022	<b>Extra Mile Achiever of the year</b> , Arokee Online Solutions Pvt. Ltd
2020 – 2021	<b>Best Performer of The Year</b> , Arokee Online Solutions Pvt. Ltd
2019 – 2020	Rookie of the vear.

Arokee Online Solutions Pvt. Ltd